VO HONG THO

Software Developer

\$\ +84901469736 @ vohongtho.infotech@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Technical Leader

2017 - Ongoing

STYL SOLUTIONS PTE LTD

Singapore

Position: Leader Team size: 26 members

Responsibility:

- Collaborate with Business Analysts/Product Owners and engage directly with our Singaporean customer to gather and clarify requirements, leading to the development of a robust system.
- Working with UI/UX designer to ensure technical feasibility of designs and functions
- Implement responsible responsive web design principles to ensure website renders well across multiple devices, browsers
- · Ensure projects pass pen test of both company and customer
- Coaches development teams in applying Scrum and DevOps
- · Collaborates across functions including areas outside of Tech
- · Builds best practices for setting up new development teams
- · Manages employee career development by providing coaching and mentoring
- Provide continuous support and guidance to less senior colleagues through regular coaching activities and support them in fulfilling their personal development plans

Team Lead 2021 - 2021

FPT Software

Position: Leader

Team size: 38 members

Description: A new and effective distribution portal is significant improvement in contact between agents, staffs and insurance company. The new portal was rebuilt to replace the two existing portal. The new portal helps to centralizing data throughout the system. Responsibility:

- Lead and hands-on technical solutions for any complex and difficult technical matters
- · Design & Development module follow requirement
- Define/implement tools and processes to standardize and automate the way project software is developed, built, tested, and deployed
- Implement responsible responsive web design principles to ensure website renders well across multiple devices, browsers
- Led multiple development processes for large scale enterprise products with above 93% product satisfaction reviews
- Technical solution consultant
- · Solving technical issue, optimize code
- · Work closely with QC team to ensure the project quality
- Ensure the assigned tasks to be performed on-time and with high quality

Team Leader 2017 - 2018

PRIME LABO CO., LTD

Ho Chi Minh

Position: Lead

Team size: 28 members

Responsibility:

Meeting with the Japanese customer, solving the problem, managing team, estimating, training fresher, researching technology

- Meeting with the Japanese customer makes clear requirement
- Managing team, estimating, solving the problem, training fresher, researching technology
- Design, develop, review, implement, and manage applications and services for the production and pre-release environments
- Understand the requirements of the customer or business and utilize this knowledge to develop applications that are consistent with this
- Provide robust coding practices, solid unit/component test coverage, and debugging code

ABOUT ME

I have over 10 years of experience in the Back-End role, with a strong focus on NodeJS. I have developed numerous projects in NodeJs, including ecommerce and IoT platforms. My expertise in .Net technology spans over 10 years as well.

In addition to my technical expertise, I have extensive experience working with international customers, including over 2 years with Japanese clients and over 4 years with Singapore clients. I have also had the opportunity to work on-site in both Singapore and South Korea.

As a leader, I have over 5 years of experience and have served as a Scrum Master for over 3 years. I am well-versed in ReactJS with over 3 years of experience and 1.5 years of experience in AngularJS.

I am a highly motivated individual with strong communication, presentation, interpersonal, and problem-solving skills. I am able to quickly adapt to new technologies and work effectively both independently and as part of a team. I have good time-management skills and place a strong emphasis on selfimprovement.

My core values include integrity, respect for others, accountability, removing roadblocks, sharing experience, and helping others. I approach both my work and life with optimism, perseverance, and responsibility, and I have assertive confidence in my ability to succeed. Although I have a tendency towards perfectionism, I am continuously working to overcome this weakness.

SKILLS

Back-End

NodeJs# · .Net Core 3.1 · ASP.NET · PHP ·

C# · Python 3

System Administration

AWS · Centos/Redhat · AWS ·

Windows Servers · Alpine/Ubuntu

Databases

MySQL · SQL Sever · PostgreSQL ·

Oracel 12c · Sqlite

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

2013 - 2017 Ho Chi Minh

FASHION STAR JOINT STOCK

ReactJS · REDUX · ANGULAR 2+ ·

Position: Back-end developer with manager role

Team size: 16 members

ANGULAR JS · Typescript · JQuery ·

SCSS · Webpack 4+ · Boostrap 4+ ·

Responsibility:

HTML5/CSS3

SKILLS

Font-End

Repositories

• Contribute e-commerce system Work closely with the Marketing team/PM to analyze functional for system

Gitlab · Github · Bitbucket

Provide hands-on leadership to the design, development, and deployment of technical

CI/CD Systems

Apply functional knowledge and technical expertise to ensure implementation, configuration, and maintenance of software applications

FPT TELECOM

Software Engineer

2011 - 2013 Ho Chi Minh

Programming website management system for FPT sales, manage database for billing

Gitlab CI · Bamboo CI

Programming management system for internal and materials FPT

Scanning Tools

• Project with 9 members (Phase 1-3) - Position: Back-end Leader/ Test Leader - Skill: ASP.NET, Silverlight, JQuery, Canvas, Map, Test, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java - Build an insurance web app.

SonarQube · Fortify · NexusIQ

Agile collaboration with other teams to ensure stable systems, successful releases and development predictability

Testing

PROJECTS

IoT Platform 2022 - Ongoing

Singapore

IoT platform for data collection, processing, visualization, and device management

Posittion: Tech Lead/Senior Software enginner

Technologies used: NodeJS (NestJS), ReactJS, PostgreSQL, AWS, RedisCache, Gitlab CI, SonarQube

EDUCATION

Information Technology

University Of Science

2005 - 2008

Website design

University Of Science

Indoor Farm

Singapore

Team size: 15 members.

A portal site for farm management, which features a crop dashboard, sensor charts, rack management, user administration, access authorization, and sensor control. Team size: 10 members.

Posittion: Tech Lead/Senior Software enginner

Technologies used: NodeJS (Adonis), Angular, PostgreSQL, AWS, RedisCache, Gitlab CI, Bamboo CI Bitbucket, SonarQube

CERTIFICATION

Professional Scrum Master

Digital Learning

2022 - Ongoing

2020 - Ongoing

Singapore

Description: Develop a web application that enables students to engage in learning through iPad devices, replacing traditional paper-based methods. Facilitate teachers to create subjects, design and implement various types of questions including drag-and-drop, multiple-choice, open-ended, and activity-based, as well as build and administer quizzes. Team size: 12 members

Position: Tech Lead/Senior Software enginner

Technologies used: NodeJS (Adonis), Angular, PostgreSQL, AWS, RedisCache, Gitlab CI/CD,

HOBBIES

Travel

Music

Healthier Choice

2021 - Ongoing

Singapore Government

Description: https://healthier-choice.hpb.gov.sg

Team size: 20 members

Position: Tech Lead/Senior Software enginner

Technologies used: .Core 3.1, Angular, PostgreSQL, AWS, RedisCache, Gitlab Cl, Bitbucket,

SonarQube, Fortify,

English

LANGUAGES

Proficient



eKiosks Ecosystem

2020 - Ongoing

Singapore Government

Description: https://www.onepa.gov.sg/about-us

Team size: 8 members Position: Tech Lead

Technologies used: .Core 3.1, Angular, PostgreSQL, AWS, Solr, ActiveMQ, TYK Gateway,

RedisCache, Gitlab Cl, Bamboo Cl, Bitbucket, SonarQube, Fortify.

PROJECTS

FAS (IoT) School Subsidy System

2019 - Ongoing

Singapore

Description: Migrate on-premise school subsidy system applications from on-premise on

AWS Cloud

Team size: 6 members Position: Leader

Technologies used: Angular, C#, SQL Server, Windows server

Npark 2018 - Ongoing

Singapore Government

Description: Providing green tree management solutions in parks

and national parks
Team size: 10 members
Position: Tech lead

Technologies used: ReactJS, PHP, MySQL, Redis Cache, Socket/MQTT, Ubuntu

Limeorange 2013 - 2017

Vietnam

Description: E-Commerce system

Team size: 8 members Position: Leader

Technologies used: ASP.Net, PHP, MYSQL, Windows Server

StartupHub Tokyo 2017

Janpan

Team size: 7 members Position: Sub-lead

Technologies used: CakePHP, MYSQL, Ubuntu

Octopus 2017

Janpan

Description: Tool for manage source code and deploy to server

Team size: 6 member

Technologies used: Laravel, ReactJs, MYSQL, Ubuntu

WAAS (IoT) 2018 - 2019

Singapore Government

Description: Providing solutions that can save the lives of elderly

patients with stroke or falling in flat

Team size: 10 members Position: Tech lead

Technologies used: Angular, C#, SQL Server, Windows server

AIA Insurance Date period

Singapore

Description: AIA provides insurance products to both individuals and businesses. Find out

more about our services and latest updates.

Team size: 38 members Position: Leader

Technologies used: ReactJs, Boilerplate, Dot Net core 3.1, PostgreSQL, ECS

EDSH (IoT) 2018 - Ongoing

Singapore

Description: Providing services to help Singapore citizen eat healthier

Team size: 14 members

Position: Leader

Technologies used: Angular, C#, SQL Server, Windows server

Payment Platform (Vending Machine and Operator 2018 - 2019 Mobile App)

Singapore - Japan - China

Description: Full-featured Platform for Vending and Self-Service / Unattended payment

acceptance

Team size: 8 members Position: Leader

Technologies used: PHP, MYSQL, Ubuntu